Track 10.4 End of Year Review
Bài 10.4 Ôn tập cuối năm
Activity 8
Bài tập 8
Listen and circle
Nghe và khoanh tròn
It's your birthday soon, Sarah.
Sắp đến sinh nhật bạn rồi, Sarah.
Are you going to have a party?
Bạn có tổ chức tiệc không?
Yes, I am.
Có.
It's going to be on Saturday.
Tiệc sẽ vào thứ Bảy.
Is your birthday on Saturday too?
Sinh nhật bạn cũng vào thứ Bảy à?
The 4th of May?
Ngày 4 tháng Năm?
No, it isn't.
Không.
It's on Friday the 3rd of May.
Sinh nhật vào thứ Sáu ngày 3 tháng Năm.
I'm going to have the party on the 4th
Mình sẽ tổ chức tiệc vào ngày 4
and then I'm going to visit my grandparents on Sunday the 5th.
và rồi mình sẽ đi thăm ông bà vào Chủ nhật ngày 5.
That's a good photo.
Ảnh đẹp đấy.
Is that your cousin?
Đó là chị họ bạn à?
Yes, that's Gloria.
Vâng, đó là Gloria.
She's two years older than me.
Chị ấy lớn hơn mình hai tuổi.
Oh, OK.
Ồ, OK.
You are 10, so she's 12.
Bạn 10 tuổi, vậy chị ấy 12 tuổi.
Yes.
Đúng vậy.
Can you tidy your room, please, Sebastian?
Con dọn phòng đi được không, Sebastian?
I did it this morning, Mum.
Con dọn sáng nay rồi, Mẹ.
I'm playing computer games now.
Con đang chơi trò chơi máy tính.
OK.
Được.
But you didn't make your bed.
Nhưng con chưa dọn giường.
You have to do it now, please.
Con phải làm bây giờ, nhé.
OK, Mum.
Được, Mẹ.
Did you go on a boat trip on holiday?
Bạn có đi du thuyền trong kỳ nghỉ không?
Yes, we did.
Có.
It was great.
Rất tuyệt.
But we didn't see any dolphins.
Nhưng bọn mình không thấy cá heo nào.
Oh, no.
Ồ, không.
Did you see a shark?
Bạn có thấy cá mập không?
No.
Không.
The biggest sea animal I saw was a jellyfish.
Động vật biển lớn nhất mình thấy là con sứa.
We saw lots of them in the water.
Bọn mình thấy rất nhiều sứa trong nước.
Where did you go yesterday?
Hôm qua bạn đi đâu?
We went to that new cafe in town.
Bọn mình đi quán cà phê mới trong phố.
We had pasta.
Bọn mình ăn mì ống.
Yummy!
Ngon!
Do they have sandwiches, too?
Họ có bánh mì kẹp không?
Yes, they do.
Có.
There are some nice salads, too.
Cũng có mấy món sa lát ngon nữa.